There are lots of wave pools in the
world, but what makes this one different
is control. You can create waves of a
specific amplitude and frequency and do
so repeatedly.
>> Can we try a 1 hertz?
>> Yeah. Do me a favor and dial up 1 hertz.
>> Amplitude will be 0.078 at 1 hertz.
>> All right, go ahead and send it from
zero, please.
And so, this is the largest wave we can
make at 1 hertz. This is based on the
motion and and power requirement for the
wave maker.
There's something a bit like surreal
about watching this cuz
it almost looks like an ocean, except
you never see waves this regular out
there.
>> Correct.
>> One of the fundamental characteristics
of a wave is its wavelength, the
distance from one crest to the next. The
first thing most people learn about
waves is they transmit energy rather
than material from one place to another.
In this case, as the wave travels to the
right, the water molecules themselves
basically move along circular paths. And
the deeper the water, the smaller this
motion. All motion stops at a depth
equal to half the wavelength. This is
known as the wave base.
But even in an ideal water wave, the
molecules do drift a bit in the
direction of wave motion. And this is
because the molecules travel faster the
higher up they are. So, they move
farther at the top of their loop than
they move backwards at the bottom,
creating a spiral path.
>> This is going to be an irregular wave.
>> This is irregular?
>> Irregular wave. So, the What you saw
earlier with the regular waves were one
frequency, one amplitude. This is what
we call a spectra or multiple
frequencies and multiple amplitudes.
You can see that there's like higher
frequency with the waves that kind of go
travel slower than the low frequency
waves, cuz low frequency waves will
travel faster and overcome them. And
that's what's making them look peaky or
kind of
dulling it out.